<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Zettelkasten on Radek Padrta</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zettelkasten on Radek Padrta</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/zet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</guid>
      <description>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.
I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.</p>
<p>I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare. It&rsquo;s not much time to prepare. If you have full time job and energetic girlfriend.</p>
<h3 id="my-study-plan">My study plan</h3>
<p>My study plan is a bit different from others certifications. I want to focus mainly on practice exams and analyze the areas where I failed during the exams. This should help me better understand the topics where I am weak, allowing me to skip over the things that don&rsquo;t need much improvement.</p>
<h3 id="first-practice-exam-attempt">First Practice Exam Attempt</h3>
<p>I made my first attempt today on the Azure portal and scored only 44%.</p>
<p>However, I don&rsquo;t feel bad about it. Scoring 44% on the first attempt is good, and I realized that I was just making some dumb mistakes and I was a bit hurry. Looking forward to next improvements.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Speaking at Mambo Jambo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/public-speaking-mambo-jambo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/public-speaking-mambo-jambo/</guid>
      <description>I worked on new things in my new job when we built a solution -&amp;gt; In a high-level overview, we built an end-to-end solution and created an automated orchestration service for our AI builds.
I presented the documentation and the solution in our meetings, and the guys from my team told me that I should present this at Mambo Jambo. Initially, I thought, &amp;ldquo;hell no,&amp;rdquo; because I can&amp;rsquo;t speak like a C1 English speaker, and I had never tried public speaking before.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I worked on new things in my new job when we built a solution -&gt; In a high-level overview, we built an end-to-end solution and created an automated orchestration service for our AI builds.</p>
<p>I presented the documentation and the solution in our meetings, and the guys from my team told me that I should present this at Mambo Jambo. Initially, I thought, &ldquo;hell no,&rdquo; because I can&rsquo;t speak like a C1 English speaker, and I had never tried public speaking before.</p>
<p>After the challenge from the team, my goals pinged my endpoint in my head and I saw an opportunity to grow a little bit there.</p>
<ul>
<li>Communication is one of the most valuable skills for DevOps Engineers.</li>
</ul>
<p>We need to present our work, we need to clearly explain the issues, etc. This is something I am still working on, and it was not long before I realized this fact.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>What is the <strong>Mambo Jambo</strong>?</em> - it is a platform for public speaking where anyone can join the presentation if is interested in the topic. The topics/talks are about Azure, AWS, Front-End, and .Net and they are organized every month by ACTUM Digital. Events are onsite in Prague.</p>
<p>Informations about upcoming Mambo Jambo events -&gt; follow this <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/m-dsk/">profile</a> or check <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/cc/mambo-jambo-tech-talks-1992309">eventbrite</a></p>
<hr>
<p>So <strong>I said yes</strong>, I will be presenting the solution that we create in our team.</p>
<p>I had two weeks to prepare the presentation and I already had some ideas on how to do it. I wanted to have something different than PowerPoint. That tool doesn&rsquo;t fit me I like some for tinkering. My first idea was to give a presentation just in the terminal, but I quickly realized that the audience would not be such nerdy :)</p>
<p>I found an advanced slides plugin in Obsidian and I decided to give it a try. I spent a few evenings building the presentation. After I built the presentation I created a static web app in Azure and I connected the web app to my custom domain.</p>
<p>At Mambo Jambo, everyone had the opportunity to open the presentation on their mobile phones. And this was something where I saw the next opportunity. If people are interested in the topic, they can click on GitHub or LinkedIn to learn more about it or about me. This was why I decided to host the presentation on my domain.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="mambo-jambo-night">Mambo Jambo Night</h2>
<p>With my girlfriend, we did three dry runs and also one online dry run with my brother. Which gives me some confidence.</p>
<p>Still, I was nervous but in a really nice way and that way pushed me to stand in front of the people.. I always try to keep a positive mind in challenging events it helps me and also the team. I remember just one sentence that I said before the presentation. &ldquo;If I don&rsquo;t poop myself in front of the people, then no worries.&rdquo; So always go to the toilet before))</p>
<p>The presentation went well, but there is so much space to improve myself, the speak, etc.</p>
<p>For the first time, I think it was ok. It can be always better and we always see the improvements in ourselves. If you do not see any, try to take feedback from others.</p>
<p>In the end, I am proud of myself for finding the courage. I was also really happy and grateful that a lot of friends came to check out my speech. Their presence gave me the power I needed to stand before the people.</p>
<p>As I mentioned, this was a new experience for me, and I don&rsquo;t think it will be the last.</p>
<p>I enjoyed it!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/mambojambo2.png" type="" alt=""  />
<img loading="lazy" src="/mambojambo1.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<hr>
<p>The presentation is done, let&rsquo;s move now to the certification. Certification progress is something that I would like to write next time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
