<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Zettelkasten on Radek Padrta</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zettelkasten on Radek Padrta</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/zet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shopify build v2 - currency / structure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/shopify-build-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/shopify-build-v2/</guid>
      <description>Currency selector After we built a language selector, I also wanted a currency selector. It should be good to have the option to send packages anywhere, and people don’t want to see everything in Czech currency. We built markets in Shopify. I divided it into three pillars:
Czech Europe International Europe and International contain a few countries which I selected, just those where I saw potential.
When we set the markets, then I needed to send rates for shipping.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Currency selector
After we built a language selector, I also wanted a currency selector. It should be good to have the option to send packages anywhere, and people don’t want to see everything in Czech currency. We built markets in Shopify. I divided it into three pillars:</p>
<ul>
<li>Czech</li>
<li>Europe</li>
<li>International</li>
</ul>
<p>Europe and International contain a few countries which I selected, just those where I saw potential.</p>
<p>When we set the markets, then I needed to send rates for shipping. I put there just test prices; this needs more time to correctly set it.</p>
<p>And that setting gives me a pretty boring currency header. I wanted to have it better… It should be nice if users already understand -&gt; “here I can select currency for my country”.</p>
<p>Then I start tinkering with a code and I put an image of currency there, and in the wrapper, we can search countries! When you hover over a particular country, you will see the currency which will be shown on the page. But this is not all.. I already set geolocation, so if you are, for example, from Canada, you should see everything with Canadian currency. It should be automatic, but you know, it’s better to be prepared :)</p>
<p>Below the currency is me, just a demo photo from 9th grade from primary school :) And the scroll bar needs some tuning too!</p>
<h2 id="structure">Structure</h2>
<p>Then I started playing with the structure of the website. Here is the plan:</p>
<p>We will have two pillars of products. Each pillar has its own collections. And when you click the collections, you will see products of each collection. It’s maybe a lot for customers.. maybe you need to give them a lot of options that they can choose from on the main page.</p>
<p>This can be a good approach if you want to show everything in one check, but I also would like to have some system in our e-shop, and I think this will provide a better user experience for customers, to navigate a little bit and really find the treasure they are searching for.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopify build v1 - language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/shopify-start-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/shopify-start-v1/</guid>
      <description>We are pushing our Home Business in these last days.
One of the things we need is an e-shop, and this is the task I’m taking care of. I was deciding between two e-commerce platforms. It was between Tilda and Shopify. The winner is Shopify, and it was a nice choice from a developer’s perspective.
First steps It was about selecting our online store Theme. I chose the Studio Theme, which was the cleanest one I saw, and I already have some vision in my mind on how to improve it.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are pushing our Home Business in these last days.</p>
<p>One of the things we need is an e-shop, and this is the task I’m taking care of. I was deciding between two e-commerce platforms. It was between Tilda and Shopify. The winner is Shopify, and it was a nice choice from a developer’s perspective.</p>
<h2 id="first-steps">First steps</h2>
<p>It was about selecting our online store Theme. I chose the Studio Theme, which was the cleanest one I saw, and I already have some vision in my mind on how to improve it.</p>
<p>I spent some time playing with the portal. It was my first experience with an e-commerce portal, and there are a lot of things I need to learn, but I’m looking forward to it!</p>
<p>When I had a demo page with a demo product ready, I tried to set up the payment methods. It took me a few hours to complete it because I was mainly stuck with Apple Pay methods, but then it somehow started working. I love those problems which are solved just by time :)</p>
<h2 id="create-local-environment-for-build">Create local environment for build</h2>
<p>I decided that would be good to switch from the Shopify portal to VSCode and try to make it more custom. So I can show a little bit of myself. And I enjoy making things prettier and user-friendly.</p>
<p>I installed Shopify CLI and Ruby on my machine and got the files from the Shopify portal. Then I connected Shopify with my GitHub account. So now I have a repo where I can push changes, and those changes can be reflected in my e-shop.</p>
<p>Mainly what I wanted to accomplish was to have a local environment and test the e-shop on my local machine. So I don’t need manual interaction with the portal to see my tests and changes.</p>
<h2 id="first-code">First code</h2>
<p>Everything is written in .liquid. I was a little bit scared because I didn’t know what it was, but then I played with it one evening with my Claude AI fellow, and we made one feature already work.</p>
<p>Now on our e-shop, if a customer wants to select a language, they will get the option to choose between two languages - Czech and English.</p>
<p>The translation needs a couple more hours, but this step will be one of the last ones.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on Madeira</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/reflection-on-madeira/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/reflection-on-madeira/</guid>
      <description>As I write this, we are six days into our Madeira exploration. Overall, I am really enjoying my time on this beautiful Portuguese island&amp;hellip; It is giving me really good practice in driving!
New road And it is a good time to reflect on my journey and set new plans for myself. There were a few changes in the last week, one of them being about my job. I decided to accept a new job offer, which means there will be a lot of new opportunities to learn in few weeks.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I write this, we are six days into our Madeira exploration. Overall, I am really enjoying my time on this beautiful Portuguese island&hellip; It is giving me really good practice in driving!</p>
<h3 id="new-road">New road</h3>
<p>And it is a good time to reflect on my journey and set new plans for myself. There were a few changes in the last week, one of them being about my job. I decided to accept a new job offer, which means there will be a lot of new opportunities to learn in few weeks. From job interviews and some of my own research, I feel like it was a good decision, and I believe it will have also a huge impact on my journey as the current job!</p>
<h3 id="home-business">Home business</h3>
<p>The second thing is about our home business. We have finished all the prep, we made a strategy, and now we are going all in. It requires some investments from our side, mainly time, which is the most valuable thing for us, but we believe it is something we can do over the next 10 years as a hobby. So LFG</p>
<h3 id="online-presence">Online Presence</h3>
<p>The third thing is about online presence. It means being more active from my side in sharing on social media. I chose LinkedIn, which is also a good place to share my journey, and I will start posting on Instagram. I have a small idea about the content, but this will need to wait for a few days until I am back home.</p>
<p>In the meantime, you can see a few pictures from Madeira and more on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/_rapad/">Instagram</a>. I would love to connect with you there!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/madeira1.jpg" type="" alt=""  />
<img loading="lazy" src="/madeira2.jpg" type="" alt=""  />
<img loading="lazy" src="/madeira3.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PR Automation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/pr-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/pr-automation/</guid>
      <description>We have a couple of codes in one repository, each creates a web application. We need to create the web app with an environment that will be short-lived, allowing someone to test the app within short time period.
We want to automate the process, and one way to do that is to build the solution through a Pull Request.
Why through Pull Request? Imagine you created an application or just some feature in your app.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We have a couple of codes in one repository, each creates a web application. We need to create the web app with an environment that will be short-lived, allowing someone to test the app within short time period.</p>
<p>We want to automate the process, and one way to do that is to build the solution through a Pull Request.</p>
<h2 id="why-through-pull-request">Why through Pull Request?</h2>
<p>Imagine you created an application or just some feature in your app. You don’t want to push it to the production environment, but rather to a short-lived environment, to ensure that everything is okay and to decide if you can merge the PR request, for example, to the main branch. The short-lived environment provides us with a space to test the application.</p>
<h2 id="how-it-works">How it works?</h2>
<p>A user on GitHub will open a Pull Request. They will then choose which application they want to build (remember, we have multiple applications/features in one repository). The user selects the option they want to build, for example, Variant2.</p>
<h4 id="how-can-the-user-choose-which-app">How can the user choose which app?</h4>
<p>In the PR, there are labels. We have created a label named Variant2. If the user selects this label and opens the PR, it will trigger the pipeline, and many things will be triggered. We will discuss this in more detail later, but first, let’s talk about our possibilities.</p>
<h3 id="what-are-our-options">What are our options?</h3>
<p>There are three types I&rsquo;m working on. There may be more options, and I would be really glad to hear your thoughts about it.</p>
<p>Our case: We have code in GitHub.
My testing includes the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Web App - Azure DevOps</li>
<li>Static Web App - Azure DevOps</li>
<li>Static Web App - GitHub Actions</li>
</ul>
<p>Let&rsquo;s discuss each, how it works at a high level, and the pros and cons.</p>
<h2 id="web-app---azure-devops">Web App - Azure DevOps</h2>
<p>We opened the PR. We didn&rsquo;t select a label. Should the pipeline be triggered? No.
Why is it not triggered? Because we are using a webhook, and we defined what will trigger it. In our case, it is when a label is added.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/PRAUT_WebhookTrigger.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>You might be wondering, what if we select a different label?
For this, we have a pipeline with many conditions that check what is needed and what is already set.</p>
<p>Here is a visualization of the flow.
<img loading="lazy" src="/PRAUT_WA.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>I will not dive into the solution, or I would be writing about it for hours. The solution is in <a href="https://github.com/radekpadrta/PRAutomation/blob/main/azure-pipelines-pr-open.yml">azure-pipelines-pr-open.yml</a>. You can check it there and you will find other pipeline there.</p>
<h5 id="what-is-cool-about-this-solution">What is cool about this solution?</h5>
<p>You can manage everything and have full control over your build. You can trigger comments for your developers, letting them know what is happening in the pipeline while they wait for the short-lived environment. It’s a flexible solution and, in my opinion, this approach is best for larger applications because it allows you to simulate everything needed in Azure. We are not just creating the Web App, we are also creating the container image, setting policies, and managing RBAC for each Web App. No need to use any tokens&hellip;everything is done through CLI and managed identity.</p>
<h5 id="what-is-bad">What is bad?</h5>
<p>You need to pay for the service plan, create additional components, and the pipeline can become larger and harder to maintain with changes. You also need to implement lifecycle management. If you want to use a web app, you need to create a container for your code and wait for boot-up until your app is ready. Typically, this takes about 6-9 minutes, even when using very basic code.</p>
<h2 id="static-web-app---azure-devops">Static Web App - Azure DevOps</h2>
<p>The trigger is the same as above. We are using a Static Web App, which means we don’t need as much in the pipeline as for a Web App. All we need is the Static Web App.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/PRAUT_SWA.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h5 id="what-is-cool">What is cool?</h5>
<p>You can create preview environments and configure them as needed. For example, you can create two or three apps in one PR by selecting two or three labels, and it is cheaper than using a Web App.</p>
<h5 id="what-is-bad-1">What is bad?</h5>
<p>It is similarly challenging to set up as a Web App and hard to maintain if there are changes.</p>
<h2 id="static-web-app---github-actions">Static Web App - GitHub Actions</h2>
<p>You need to set up the connection between the Static Web App and GitHub. You can follow this guide to do that: <a href="https://github.com/radekpadrta/PRAutomation/tree/testPR">How to conenct SWA with GitHub</a></p>
<p>Once you set the connection, a pipeline for GitHub Actions will be automatically created in your repository.</p>
<p>This automatically created pipeline is not ideal for our use case, but if we make it prettier, it can be very useful!</p>
<p>The udpated pipeline can be found <a href="https://github.com/radekpadrta/PRAutomation/blob/main/.github/workflows/azure-static-web-apps-black-hill-01e38be0f.yml">here</a></p>
<p>We don’t need to worry about webhooks or payloads, and we don’t use any conditions. Everything is handled in a different way, which we don&rsquo;t see.</p>
<p>The only things we need to configure is how to get the URL of the preview environment and how to choose which app we want to build.</p>
<h5 id="what-is-cool-1">What is cool?</h5>
<p>If the code is in GitHub, it’s easy to set up Actions, understand, and maintain. One PR = One App. I working now on how to make it more flexible, so hopefully, in the next post, there will be some progress. But overall, it&rsquo;s best solution.</p>
<h5 id="what-is-bad-2">What is bad?</h5>
<p>We don’t work with the payload, making it difficult to create flexible tasks. Additionally, we don’t see what is happening in GitHub Actions, for example when it sends information to users.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>If you have a lot of time, want to be sure everything is set up according to your needs, and you have money, go for the Web App.</p>
<p>If you have some time, and already Azure set for your Web App environments, and want to test the solution and discard it without incurring high costs, choose the Static Web App.</p>
<p>If you want an easy solution, don’t want to spend much time on it, and don’t need a highly flexible setup, go with the Static Web App using GitHub Actions.</p>
<h4 id="links">LINKS:</h4>
<p>16-08-2024-08:49</p>
<hr>
<p>[[]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a home business 🏡</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/create-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/create-business/</guid>
      <description>Idea On 14.7.24, my girlfriend and I came up with an idea. We watched a video on how to start a business. It was the first video related to this topic which we watched, and after that, we brainstormed together to figure out a topic we both liked.
We got some ideas, and our journey start that day. :)
Research and Development I can’t tell right now what we want to do.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="idea">Idea</h2>
<p>On 14.7.24, my girlfriend and I came up with an idea. We watched a video on how to start a business. It was the first video related to this topic which we watched, and after that, we brainstormed together to figure out a topic we both liked.</p>
<p>We got some ideas, and our journey start that day. :)</p>
<h3 id="research-and-development">Research and Development</h3>
<p>I can’t tell right now what we want to do.. this will be a little surprise. What I can tell is that we are doing a lot of research on how to create and build our product and how to satisfy our future customers. We also know that there may be no success, and we could invest money in something that might not return anything.</p>
<p>We are aware of the risk, but we still decided to give it a try. It is a really good experience to have, and for our personal growth, it can be just beneficial.</p>
<p>So, let’s grab it and share this journey!</p>
<h3 id="revised-focus">Revised Focus</h3>
<p>Initially, I planned to write primarily about the Cloud/DevOps journey and explore the Kubernetes field. While that is still on the program, the priority has changed little bit. I now want to share our experience in building a small home business.</p>
<p>But looking forward to jump and learn that field.</p>
<h4 id="sneak-peek">Sneak Peek</h4>
<p>AI</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation of Pull Requests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/automationofthepr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/automationofthepr/</guid>
      <description>Automation Process One of my projects was to create an automation process to build a Web App when a PR is created.
Anyone with access to the Repo can easily build the WebApp for their Use Case, for example to quickly build a webpage with something for an individual client. No need to come to a Developer and say we need this and the developer will spend time to prepare the thing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="automation-process">Automation Process</h3>
<p>One of my projects was to create an automation process to build a Web App when a PR is created.</p>
<p>Anyone with access to the Repo can easily build the WebApp for their Use Case, for example to quickly build a webpage with something for an individual client. No need to come to a Developer and say we need this and the developer will spend time to prepare the thing. The Web App should be like a template for users.</p>
<p>I have prepared an environment which needs to be built if the solution is needed. So imagine Franta Flinta needs a web app which can be shown in a presentation.</p>
<p>He will come to GitHub and he will create a PR request. He puts a label &ldquo;Create Environment&rdquo; there and the magic starts.</p>
<h3 id="pipeline-workflow">Pipeline Workflow</h3>
<p>Choosing the label &ldquo;Create Environment&rdquo;, triggers the pipeline. The Pipeline is creating the whole process.</p>
<ul>
<li>Building the ACR image</li>
<li>Creating the App Service Plan</li>
<li>Creating the Web App</li>
<li>Assigning Managed Identity</li>
<li>Assigning AcrPull Role</li>
<li>Setting env variables</li>
<li>Restarting the Web App</li>
</ul>
<p>Web App In the repo we have the code and Dockerfile prepared.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s the same with closing PR. If you unlabeled the label or close the PR, there is another Pipeline which destroys everything that was built.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;re now thinking how the user will get the address back to the GitHub repo?
We are using just webhooks and the webhook payload can be accessed in the Pipeline. So we are checking the number.</p>
<p>The number references the issue/PR and then we know where we need to send the comments.
So after correct steps we always inform the user about the process of the solution.</p>
<h3 id="solution">Solution</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/Autoamtion.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h3 id="improvements">Improvements?</h3>
<p>Yes, there are, and these are everywhere.</p>
<p>What I want to do is to create an action to check how long the Web App has been up, so we can remove it after a certain time period and save money.
Also, there can be some field in the PR which can be extracted in the Pipeline, and the Pipeline will assign the variable into the Code.
Lastly, what I&rsquo;m thinking is to get info to the user if something bad happened during the creation of the solution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104 - Done 🎉</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/</guid>
      <description>Few days before exam For my last preparation, I reviewed John Savill&amp;rsquo;s Study Cram which can be found here Road to Azure v2. And I did one test with 50-60 questions (about 1-2 hour for each) every day. Two days ago I got only 70% and the mood was not ok. I tested myself in my hometown when I visited my family so there was distraction to get the test done.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="few-days-before-exam">Few days before exam</h3>
<p>For my last preparation, I reviewed John Savill&rsquo;s Study Cram which can be found here <a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/">Road to Azure v2</a>. And I did one test with 50-60 questions (about 1-2 hour for each) every day. Two days ago I got only 70% and the mood was not ok. I tested myself in my hometown when I visited my family so there was distraction to get the test done. I woke up early the next day before the test day and tried another exam and I got 92%, so it gave me some confidence.</p>
<p>In the evening I watched the last 1 hour from Study cram and then I shut down my brain. I wanted to not think about the exam, just think about the present moment.</p>
<h3 id="test-day">Test day</h3>
<p>I took the exam at 8AM so I woke up at 6AM, got a huge breakfast from my girlfriend, watched some YT videos, hit the toilet a few times and then I went to the exam. On the way to the test center I listened to some dopamine boost music. Then I hit the toilet one more time and here we go.</p>
<h3 id="the-two-hour-challenge">The Two-Hour Challenge</h3>
<p>The test was for two hours, when I sat at the computer I wasn&rsquo;t really nervous as I was supposed to be in the past. It&rsquo;s just a certification..</p>
<p>But after a few questions I was nervous. The certification was really tough! I got thoughts like: &ldquo;When can I schedule the next attempt&rdquo;, &ldquo;I am totally confused&rdquo;, &ldquo;The time is ticking, no time&rdquo;.. and these thoughts made me nervous.
In another way there was still the spirit in a different part of my head, that said, fuck it be logical and just read the question, don&rsquo;t think so much about the question and just try to make it.</p>
<p>The spirit was the correct one.</p>
<h2 id="we-finished-it">We finished it!</h2>
<p>After 2 hours I saw the result and there was PASS. I didn&rsquo;t say anything in my head. I just smiled at the monitor. We managed it and we beat it!</p>
<p>Some of these questions were really something I hadn&rsquo;t experienced. And that means there is huge room to improve my skills!</p>
<p>And here are these:
<img loading="lazy" src="/AZCerts.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to Azure v1</a>
<a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/">Road to Azure v2</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104 v2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/</guid>
      <description>How is it going with Road to AZ104?
At the start, I felt a lot of energy. I make at least one test every day, which takes approximately 1-2 hours.
I tested myself on Cloud Guru, Azure Learning, and I am newly testing myself on Examtopics, which was suggested by my colleague. There are actual questions from the exam, but I think the approach to memorizing them&amp;hellip; there is soo much question, I dont have brain for it:)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How is it going with <a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to AZ104</a>?</p>
<hr>
<p>At the start, I felt a lot of energy. I make at least one test every day, which takes approximately 1-2 hours.</p>
<p>I tested myself on Cloud Guru, Azure Learning, and I am newly testing myself on Examtopics, which was suggested by my colleague. There are actual questions from the exam, but I think the approach to memorizing them&hellip; there is soo much question, I dont have brain for it:)</p>
<p>Need to say I got a more than 70% only a few times&hellip;</p>
<p>In the meantime, I watched John Savill&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9DuTWSvsLXM&amp;t=3711s&amp;ab_channel=JohnSavill%27sTechnicalTraining">Networking Master Class</a>. Networking is a part that I am not strong in, so I am trying to work on it.</p>
<p>I also started watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Knf9nub4-k&amp;t=3275s&amp;ab_channel=JohnSavill%27sTechnicalTraining">Azure 104 Study Cram</a> from John Savill, which I think gave me a lot. I want to watch it one more time.</p>
<p>I need to mention, I don&rsquo;t take many notes. I take notes only if I fail on some questions, but I do not take notes through the videos. This can be a problem, but I need to think positively before the test. After the fight, we can try a different way.</p>
<p>The plan is to focus mainly next week on the exam and check the Study Cram one more time. And then take action!</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s see if we can make it :)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to Azure v1</a>
<a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/">Road to Azure v3</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature flags - App Configuration and Web App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/feature-flags/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/feature-flags/</guid>
      <description>This article is about finding a way how to create feature flags on a Web app or App configuration. This is the result of my notes, where I tried to find a solution.
Environment Variables On Azure web app, there is an option to use environment variables, but it is not a good approach if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to get alerts. The alerts can be created because your app will be restarted if you assign the variable.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This article is about finding a way how to create feature flags on a Web app or App configuration. This is the result of my notes, where I tried to find a solution.</p>
<h3 id="environment-variables">Environment Variables</h3>
<p>On Azure web app, there is an option to use <strong>environment variables</strong>, but it is not a good approach if you don&rsquo;t want to get alerts. The alerts can be created because your app will be restarted if you assign the variable. The app will be offline for some time. This means if you need to rewrite the variable in the future, you always need to restart the app. So this option was out because of the bigger web app, and we did not want to have it offline for some time.</p>
<h3 id="feature-flags">Feature Flags</h3>
<p>Another option was to use <strong>Feature flags</strong> in the App Configuration service. Feature flags are in the <strong>Feature manager</strong> in App Configuration. The feature flags can be called only through SDK; there is no REST API, and that was the problem. Because if you want to use SDK, you need to install some library, and in our case, it was nugets, and that was a no-go.</p>
<p>So how we can make the Feature flags work?</p>
<h3 id="key-value">Key Value</h3>
<p>The approach was to use <strong>Key Value</strong> which can be found in <strong>Configuration explorer</strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/configExplorer.png" type="" alt=""  />
But I found the authorization through REST API a little bit more complicated than usual. You need to get a Bearer token first and then reach the endpoint.</p>
<p>And this is how you can get the token:
<img loading="lazy" src="/GetToken.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code class="language-RestAPI" data-lang="RestAPI">POST https://login.microsoftonline.com/ad9ab3ca-16d5-496d-8591-b7f91a515135/oauth2/v2.0/token
Body - x-www-form-urlencoded
Values:
client_id:value
client_secret:value
grant_type:client_credentials
scope:https://management.azure.com/.default
</code></pre><p>Unfortunately, the Bearer token is a little bit complicated to get, and you need to use ClientID and Client Secret from your App Registration, and this is something that needs to be changed. But it is ok if you want this approach, you just need to store these values in Key Vault and reference the Key Vault in your code.</p>
<hr>
<p>And this is the URL how to get the endpoint for KeyValue (GET)</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-Rest" data-lang="Rest"><span class="line"><span class="cl">https://management.azure.com/subscriptions/SubscriptionID/resourceGroups/RGname/providers/Microsoft.AppConfiguration/configurationStores/AppConfigurationName/keyValues/NameOfKeyValue$NameOfLabel?api-version=2023-03-01<span class="err">
</span></span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="/GetKeyValue.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<hr>
<p>Our approach is upgrade the solution to used managed identity to communicate with the App Configuration, but how we do that. This will be added later.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="pipeline">Pipeline</h3>
<p>This can be used in Pipeline if we need to use feature flags.</p>
<p>In the pipeline approach, this should work to get info about a Feature flag from Feature manager.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code class="language-Azure" data-lang="Azure">az appconfig feature show -n NameOfTheAppConfiguration --key .appconfig.featureflag/NameOfTheFeatureFlag --subscription xxx
</code></pre>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and Hosting an AI Solution Using Prompt Flow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/creating-and-hosting-an-ai-solution-using-prompt-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/creating-and-hosting-an-ai-solution-using-prompt-flow/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about why we chose the Prompt Flow. In the AI world, we wanted to have one place where we could build our AI solutions and we wanted to have platform where other developers could easily collaborate. And this is a great use case for Prompt Flow, which works as an orchestration tool for our builds.
We built two solutions. Our vision was to get metadata from some article and alternative text from pictures, and then each solution needed a final step: a translator to translate the results into different languages.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about why we chose the Prompt Flow.
In the AI world, we wanted to have one place where we could build our AI solutions and  we wanted to have platform where other developers could easily collaborate. And this is a great use case for Prompt Flow, which works as an orchestration tool for our builds.</p>
<p>We built two solutions. Our vision was to get metadata from some article and alternative text from pictures, and then each solution needed a final step: a translator to translate the results into different languages.</p>
<p>And these two solutions were created through the Prompt Flow. <a href="https://github.com/radekpadrta/MamboJambo_PromptFlow">Source code here</a></p>
<p>When we built the solution through Prompt Flow, our next step was to create an endpoint where the solution could be hosted and wait for travelers (requests).</p>
<h3 id="how-did-we-do-that">How Did We Do That?</h3>
<p>When we create builds on Prompt flow, we used the Machine Learning Workspace, which also has an option to create the endpoint. Creating the endpoint was a simple task, but how could we assign the Prompt Flow solution to the endpoint, right?</p>
<h3 id="where-the-fun-begins">Where the Fun Begins</h3>
<p>The solution needs to be packaged first, and that the need for us to create a <strong>model</strong> in MLW. It means: Prompt Flow build become a Model. Once we have the model, we can create an empty endpoint, which will wait for our model. However, to complete this, we need to create an Environment.</p>
<p>The Environment for building our model needs to be somehow added to the endpoint, and the environment is something that will handle the deployment. If you remember from the start, I mentioned that our use case also needed a translator, right? This is a small problem for the environment because we can&rsquo;t use a pre-built environment and we need to create our own.</p>
<h3 id="why">Why?</h3>
<p>The translator isn&rsquo;t included by default in Prompt Flow, but you can install packages in Prompt Flow. That is why you need to have the package also in your environment. We used a predefined image and we added the RUN command for the translator package. That is how we built the environment through Dockerfile and ACR. We hosted the Docker image in Azure Container Registry.</p>
<p>Ok, we have Prompt Flow (Builds) - Model - Endpoint (Empty) - Environment. So what is the next and the last step to push travelers(request) to the castle(endpoint) ?</p>
<h3 id="deployment-facing-the-final-boss">Deployment: Facing the Final Boss</h3>
<p>Deployment
This is last boss who is waiting for us and need to be finished. Here we need to gather all the information about our previous road - model, environment, and the endpoint need to be entered to the deployment, but we also need to provide SKU (VM) and assign the traffic.</p>
<p>Then if we get green light, the boss is finished and our castle can welcome travelers.</p>
<p>More about the project will be added soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</guid>
      <description>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.
I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.</p>
<p>I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare. It&rsquo;s not much time to prepare. If you have full time job and energetic girlfriend.</p>
<h3 id="my-study-plan">My study plan</h3>
<p>My study plan is a bit different from others certifications. I want to focus mainly on practice exams and analyze the areas where I failed during the exams. This should help me better understand the topics where I am weak, allowing me to skip over the things that don&rsquo;t need much improvement.</p>
<h3 id="first-practice-exam-attempt">First Practice Exam Attempt</h3>
<p>I made my first attempt today on the Azure portal and scored only 44%.</p>
<p>However, I don&rsquo;t feel bad about it. Scoring 44% on the first attempt is good, and I realized that I was just making some dumb mistakes and I was a bit hurry. Looking forward to next improvements.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/">Road to Azure v2</a>
<a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/">Road to Azure v3</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Speaking at Mambo Jambo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/public-speaking-mambo-jambo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/public-speaking-mambo-jambo/</guid>
      <description>I worked on new things in my new job when we built a solution -&amp;gt; In a high-level overview, we built an end-to-end solution and created an automated orchestration service for our AI builds.
I presented the documentation and the solution in our meetings, and the guys from my team told me that I should present this at Mambo Jambo. Initially, I thought, &amp;ldquo;hell no,&amp;rdquo; because I can&amp;rsquo;t speak like a C1 English speaker, and I had never tried public speaking before.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I worked on new things in my new job when we built a solution -&gt; In a high-level overview, we built an end-to-end solution and created an automated orchestration service for our AI builds.</p>
<p>I presented the documentation and the solution in our meetings, and the guys from my team told me that I should present this at Mambo Jambo. Initially, I thought, &ldquo;hell no,&rdquo; because I can&rsquo;t speak like a C1 English speaker, and I had never tried public speaking before.</p>
<p>After the challenge from the team, my goals pinged my endpoint in my head and I saw an opportunity to grow a little bit there.</p>
<ul>
<li>Communication is one of the most valuable skills for DevOps Engineers.</li>
</ul>
<p>We need to present our work, we need to clearly explain the issues, etc. This is something I am still working on, and it was not long before I realized this fact.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>What is the <strong>Mambo Jambo</strong>?</em> - it is a platform for public speaking where anyone can join the presentation if is interested in the topic. The topics/talks are about Azure, AWS, Front-End, and .Net and they are organized every month by ACTUM Digital. Events are onsite in Prague.</p>
<p>Informations about upcoming Mambo Jambo events -&gt; follow this <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/m-dsk/">profile</a> or check <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/cc/mambo-jambo-tech-talks-1992309">eventbrite</a></p>
<hr>
<p>So <strong>I said yes</strong>, I will be presenting the solution that we create in our team.</p>
<p>I had two weeks to prepare the presentation and I already had some ideas on how to do it. I wanted to have something different than PowerPoint. That tool doesn&rsquo;t fit me I like some for tinkering. My first idea was to give a presentation just in the terminal, but I quickly realized that the audience would not be such nerdy :)</p>
<p>I found an advanced slides plugin in Obsidian and I decided to give it a try. I spent a few evenings building the presentation. After I built the presentation I created a static web app in Azure and I connected the web app to my custom domain.</p>
<p>At Mambo Jambo, everyone had the opportunity to open the presentation on their mobile phones. And this was something where I saw the next opportunity. If people are interested in the topic, they can click on GitHub or LinkedIn to learn more about it or about me. This was why I decided to host the presentation on my domain.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="mambo-jambo-night">Mambo Jambo Night</h2>
<p>With my girlfriend, we did three dry runs and also one online dry run with my brother. Which gives me some confidence.</p>
<p>Still, I was nervous but in a really nice way and that way pushed me to stand in front of the people.. I always try to keep a positive mind in challenging events it helps me and also the team. I remember just one sentence that I said before the presentation. &ldquo;If I don&rsquo;t poop myself in front of the people, then no worries.&rdquo; So always go to the toilet before))</p>
<p>The presentation went well, but there is so much space to improve myself, the speak, etc.</p>
<p>For the first time, I think it was ok. It can be always better and we always see the improvements in ourselves. If you do not see any, try to take feedback from others.</p>
<p>In the end, I am proud of myself for finding the courage. I was also really happy and grateful that a lot of friends came to check out my speech. Their presence gave me the power I needed to stand before the people.</p>
<p>As I mentioned, this was a new experience for me, and I don&rsquo;t think it will be the last.</p>
<p>I enjoyed it!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/mambojambo2.png" type="" alt=""  />
<img loading="lazy" src="/mambojambo1.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<hr>
<p>The presentation is done, let&rsquo;s move now to the certification. Certification progress is something that I would like to write next time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
