<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Business on Radek Padrta</title>
    <link>http://localhost:52531/tags/home-business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Business on Radek Padrta</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:52531/cloudhammer.svg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:52531/cloudhammer.svg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:52531/tags/home-business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shopify build v2 - currency / structure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52531/zet/articles/shopify-build-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:52531/zet/articles/shopify-build-v2/</guid>
      <description>Currency selector After we built a language selector, I also wanted a currency selector. It should be good to have the option to send packages anywhere, and people don’t want to see everything in Czech currency. We built markets in Shopify. I divided it into three pillars:
Czech Europe International Europe and International contain a few countries which I selected, just those where I saw potential.
When we set the markets, then I needed to send rates for shipping.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Currency selector
After we built a language selector, I also wanted a currency selector. It should be good to have the option to send packages anywhere, and people don’t want to see everything in Czech currency. We built markets in Shopify. I divided it into three pillars:</p>
<ul>
<li>Czech</li>
<li>Europe</li>
<li>International</li>
</ul>
<p>Europe and International contain a few countries which I selected, just those where I saw potential.</p>
<p>When we set the markets, then I needed to send rates for shipping. I put there just test prices; this needs more time to correctly set it.</p>
<p>And that setting gives me a pretty boring currency header. I wanted to have it better… It should be nice if users already understand -&gt; “here I can select currency for my country”.</p>
<p>Then I start tinkering with a code and I put an image of currency there, and in the wrapper, we can search countries! When you hover over a particular country, you will see the currency which will be shown on the page. But this is not all.. I already set geolocation, so if you are, for example, from Canada, you should see everything with Canadian currency. It should be automatic, but you know, it’s better to be prepared :)</p>
<p>Below the currency is me, just a demo photo from 9th grade from primary school :) And the scroll bar needs some tuning too!</p>
<h2 id="structure">Structure</h2>
<p>Then I started playing with the structure of the website. Here is the plan:</p>
<p>We will have two pillars of products. Each pillar has its own collections. And when you click the collections, you will see products of each collection. It’s maybe a lot for customers.. maybe you need to give them a lot of options that they can choose from on the main page.</p>
<p>This can be a good approach if you want to show everything in one check, but I also would like to have some system in our e-shop, and I think this will provide a better user experience for customers, to navigate a little bit and really find the treasure they are searching for.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopify build v1 - language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52531/zet/articles/shopify-start-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:52531/zet/articles/shopify-start-v1/</guid>
      <description>We are pushing our Home Business in these last days.
One of the things we need is an e-shop, and this is the task I’m taking care of. I was deciding between two e-commerce platforms. It was between Tilda and Shopify. The winner is Shopify, and it was a nice choice from a developer’s perspective.
First steps It was about selecting our online store Theme. I chose the Studio Theme, which was the cleanest one I saw, and I already have some vision in my mind on how to improve it.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are pushing our Home Business in these last days.</p>
<p>One of the things we need is an e-shop, and this is the task I’m taking care of. I was deciding between two e-commerce platforms. It was between Tilda and Shopify. The winner is Shopify, and it was a nice choice from a developer’s perspective.</p>
<h2 id="first-steps">First steps</h2>
<p>It was about selecting our online store Theme. I chose the Studio Theme, which was the cleanest one I saw, and I already have some vision in my mind on how to improve it.</p>
<p>I spent some time playing with the portal. It was my first experience with an e-commerce portal, and there are a lot of things I need to learn, but I’m looking forward to it!</p>
<p>When I had a demo page with a demo product ready, I tried to set up the payment methods. It took me a few hours to complete it because I was mainly stuck with Apple Pay methods, but then it somehow started working. I love those problems which are solved just by time :)</p>
<h2 id="create-local-environment-for-build">Create local environment for build</h2>
<p>I decided that would be good to switch from the Shopify portal to VSCode and try to make it more custom. So I can show a little bit of myself. And I enjoy making things prettier and user-friendly.</p>
<p>I installed Shopify CLI and Ruby on my machine and got the files from the Shopify portal. Then I connected Shopify with my GitHub account. So now I have a repo where I can push changes, and those changes can be reflected in my e-shop.</p>
<p>Mainly what I wanted to accomplish was to have a local environment and test the e-shop on my local machine. So I don’t need manual interaction with the portal to see my tests and changes.</p>
<h2 id="first-code">First code</h2>
<p>Everything is written in .liquid. I was a little bit scared because I didn’t know what it was, but then I played with it one evening with my Claude AI fellow, and we made one feature already work.</p>
<p>Now on our e-shop, if a customer wants to select a language, they will get the option to choose between two languages - Czech and English.</p>
<p>The translation needs a couple more hours, but this step will be one of the last ones.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a home business 🏡</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52531/zet/articles/create-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:52531/zet/articles/create-business/</guid>
      <description>Idea On 14.7.24, my girlfriend and I came up with an idea. We watched a video on how to start a business. It was the first video related to this topic which we watched, and after that, we brainstormed together to figure out a topic we both liked.
We got some ideas, and our journey start that day. :)
Research and Development I can’t tell right now what we want to do.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="idea">Idea</h2>
<p>On 14.7.24, my girlfriend and I came up with an idea. We watched a video on how to start a business. It was the first video related to this topic which we watched, and after that, we brainstormed together to figure out a topic we both liked.</p>
<p>We got some ideas, and our journey start that day. :)</p>
<h3 id="research-and-development">Research and Development</h3>
<p>I can’t tell right now what we want to do.. this will be a little surprise. What I can tell is that we are doing a lot of research on how to create and build our product and how to satisfy our future customers. We also know that there may be no success, and we could invest money in something that might not return anything.</p>
<p>We are aware of the risk, but we still decided to give it a try. It is a really good experience to have, and for our personal growth, it can be just beneficial.</p>
<p>So, let’s grab it and share this journey!</p>
<h3 id="revised-focus">Revised Focus</h3>
<p>Initially, I planned to write primarily about the Cloud/DevOps journey and explore the Kubernetes field. While that is still on the program, the priority has changed little bit. I now want to share our experience in building a small home business.</p>
<p>But looking forward to jump and learn that field.</p>
<h4 id="sneak-peek">Sneak Peek</h4>
<p>AI</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
