<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Radek Padrta</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Radek Padrta</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automation of Pull Requests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/automationofthepr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/automationofthepr/</guid>
      <description>Automation Process One of my projects was to create an automation process to build a Web App when a PR is created.
Anyone with access to the Repo can easily build the WebApp for their Use Case, for example to quickly build a webpage with something for an individual client. No need to come to a Developer and say we need this and the developer will spend time to prepare the thing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="automation-process">Automation Process</h3>
<p>One of my projects was to create an automation process to build a Web App when a PR is created.</p>
<p>Anyone with access to the Repo can easily build the WebApp for their Use Case, for example to quickly build a webpage with something for an individual client. No need to come to a Developer and say we need this and the developer will spend time to prepare the thing. The Web App should be like a template for users.</p>
<p>I have prepared an environment which needs to be built if the solution is needed. So imagine Franta Flinta needs a web app which can be shown in a presentation.</p>
<p>He will come to GitHub and he will create a PR request. He puts a label &ldquo;Create Environment&rdquo; there and the magic starts.</p>
<h3 id="pipeline-workflow">Pipeline Workflow</h3>
<p>Choosing the label &ldquo;Create Environment&rdquo;, triggers the pipeline. The Pipeline is creating the whole process.</p>
<ul>
<li>Building the ACR image</li>
<li>Creating the App Service Plan</li>
<li>Creating the Web App</li>
<li>Assigning Managed Identity</li>
<li>Assigning AcrPull Role</li>
<li>Setting env variables</li>
<li>Restarting the Web App</li>
</ul>
<p>Web App In the repo we have the code and Dockerfile prepared.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s the same with closing PR. If you unlabeled the label or close the PR, there is another Pipeline which destroys everything that was built.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;re now thinking how the user will get the address back to the GitHub repo?
We are using just webhooks and the webhook payload can be accessed in the Pipeline. So we are checking the number.</p>
<p>The number references the issue/PR and then we know where we need to send the comments.
So after correct steps we always inform the user about the process of the solution.</p>
<h3 id="solution">Solution</h3>
<p></p>
<h3 id="improvements">Improvements?</h3>
<p>Yes, there are, and these are everywhere.</p>
<p>What I want to do is to create an action to check how long the Web App has been up, so we can remove it after a certain time period and save money.
Also, there can be some field in the PR which can be extracted in the Pipeline, and the Pipeline will assign the variable into the Code.
Lastly, what I&rsquo;m thinking is to get info to the user if something bad happened during the creation of the solution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104 - Done 🎉</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/</guid>
      <description>Few days before exam For my last preparation, I reviewed John Savill&amp;rsquo;s Study Cram which can be found here Road to Azure v2. And I did one test with 50-60 questions (about 1-2 hour for each) every day. Two days ago I got only 70% and the mood was not ok. I tested myself in my hometown when I visited my family so there was distraction to get the test done.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="few-days-before-exam">Few days before exam</h3>
<p>For my last preparation, I reviewed John Savill&rsquo;s Study Cram which can be found here <a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/">Road to Azure v2</a>. And I did one test with 50-60 questions (about 1-2 hour for each) every day. Two days ago I got only 70% and the mood was not ok. I tested myself in my hometown when I visited my family so there was distraction to get the test done. I woke up early the next day before the test day and tried another exam and I got 92%, so it gave me some confidence.</p>
<p>In the evening I watched the last 1 hour from Study cram and then I shut down my brain. I wanted to not think about the exam, just think about the present moment.</p>
<h3 id="test-day">Test day</h3>
<p>I took the exam at 8AM so I woke up at 6AM, got a huge breakfast from my girlfriend, watched some YT videos, hit the toilet a few times and then I went to the exam. On the way to the test center I listened to some dopamine boost music. Then I hit the toilet one more time and here we go.</p>
<h3 id="the-two-hour-challenge">The Two-Hour Challenge</h3>
<p>The test was for two hours, when I sat at the computer I wasn&rsquo;t really nervous as I was supposed to be in the past. It&rsquo;s just a certification..</p>
<p>But after a few questions I was nervous. The certification was really tough! I got thoughts like: &ldquo;When can I schedule the next attempt&rdquo;, &ldquo;I am totally confused&rdquo;, &ldquo;The time is ticking, no time&rdquo;.. and these thoughts made me nervous.
In another way there was still the spirit in a different part of my head, that said, fuck it be logical and just read the question, don&rsquo;t think so much about the question and just try to make it.</p>
<p>The spirit was the correct one.</p>
<h2 id="we-finished-it">We finished it!</h2>
<p>After 2 hours I saw the result and there was PASS. I didn&rsquo;t say anything in my head. I just smiled at the monitor. We managed it and we beat it!</p>
<p>Some of these questions were really something I hadn&rsquo;t experienced. And that means there is huge room to improve my skills!</p>
<p>And here are these:
<img loading="lazy" src="/AZCerts.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to Azure v1</a>
<a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/">Road to Azure v2</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104 v2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/</guid>
      <description>How is it going with Road to AZ104?
At the start, I felt a lot of energy. I make at least one test every day, which takes approximately 1-2 hours.
I tested myself on Cloud Guru, Azure Learning, and I am newly testing myself on Examtopics, which was suggested by my colleague. There are actual questions from the exam, but I think the approach to memorizing them&amp;hellip; there is soo much question, I dont have brain for it:)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How is it going with <a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to AZ104</a>?</p>
<hr>
<p>At the start, I felt a lot of energy. I make at least one test every day, which takes approximately 1-2 hours.</p>
<p>I tested myself on Cloud Guru, Azure Learning, and I am newly testing myself on Examtopics, which was suggested by my colleague. There are actual questions from the exam, but I think the approach to memorizing them&hellip; there is soo much question, I dont have brain for it:)</p>
<p>Need to say I got a more than 70% only a few times&hellip;</p>
<p>In the meantime, I watched John Savill&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9DuTWSvsLXM&amp;t=3711s&amp;ab_channel=JohnSavill%27sTechnicalTraining">Networking Master Class</a>. Networking is a part that I am not strong in, so I am trying to work on it.</p>
<p>I also started watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Knf9nub4-k&amp;t=3275s&amp;ab_channel=JohnSavill%27sTechnicalTraining">Azure 104 Study Cram</a> from John Savill, which I think gave me a lot. I want to watch it one more time.</p>
<p>I need to mention, I don&rsquo;t take many notes. I take notes only if I fail on some questions, but I do not take notes through the videos. This can be a problem, but I need to think positively before the test. After the fight, we can try a different way.</p>
<p>The plan is to focus mainly next week on the exam and check the Study Cram one more time. And then take action!</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s see if we can make it :)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to Azure v1</a>
<a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/">Road to Azure v3</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature flags - App Configuration and Web App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/feature-flags/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/feature-flags/</guid>
      <description>This article is about finding a way how to create feature flags on a Web app or App configuration. This is the result of my notes, where I tried to find a solution.
Environment Variables On Azure web app, there is an option to use environment variables, but it is not a good approach if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to get alerts. The alerts can be created because your app will be restarted if you assign the variable.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This article is about finding a way how to create feature flags on a Web app or App configuration. This is the result of my notes, where I tried to find a solution.</p>
<h3 id="environment-variables">Environment Variables</h3>
<p>On Azure web app, there is an option to use <strong>environment variables</strong>, but it is not a good approach if you don&rsquo;t want to get alerts. The alerts can be created because your app will be restarted if you assign the variable. The app will be offline for some time. This means if you need to rewrite the variable in the future, you always need to restart the app. So this option was out because of the bigger web app, and we did not want to have it offline for some time.</p>
<h3 id="feature-flags">Feature Flags</h3>
<p>Another option was to use <strong>Feature flags</strong> in the App Configuration service. Feature flags are in the <strong>Feature manager</strong> in App Configuration. The feature flags can be called only through SDK; there is no REST API, and that was the problem. Because if you want to use SDK, you need to install some library, and in our case, it was nugets, and that was a no-go.</p>
<p>So how we can make the Feature flags work?</p>
<h3 id="key-value">Key Value</h3>
<p>The approach was to use <strong>Key Value</strong> which can be found in <strong>Configuration explorer</strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/configExplorer.png" type="" alt=""  />
But I found the authorization through REST API a little bit more complicated than usual. You need to get a Bearer token first and then reach the endpoint.</p>
<p>And this is how you can get the token:
<img loading="lazy" src="/GetToken.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code class="language-RestAPI" data-lang="RestAPI">POST https://login.microsoftonline.com/ad9ab3ca-16d5-496d-8591-b7f91a515135/oauth2/v2.0/token
Body - x-www-form-urlencoded
Values:
client_id:value
client_secret:value
grant_type:client_credentials
scope:https://management.azure.com/.default
</code></pre><p>Unfortunately, the Bearer token is a little bit complicated to get, and you need to use ClientID and Client Secret from your App Registration, and this is something that needs to be changed. But it is ok if you want this approach, you just need to store these values in Key Vault and reference the Key Vault in your code.</p>
<hr>
<p>And this is the URL how to get the endpoint for KeyValue (GET)</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-Rest" data-lang="Rest"><span class="line"><span class="cl">https://management.azure.com/subscriptions/SubscriptionID/resourceGroups/RGname/providers/Microsoft.AppConfiguration/configurationStores/AppConfigurationName/keyValues/NameOfKeyValue$NameOfLabel?api-version=2023-03-01<span class="err">
</span></span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="/GetKeyValue.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<hr>
<p>Our approach is upgrade the solution to used managed identity to communicate with the App Configuration, but how we do that. This will be added later.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="pipeline">Pipeline</h3>
<p>This can be used in Pipeline if we need to use feature flags.</p>
<p>In the pipeline approach, this should work to get info about a Feature flag from Feature manager.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code class="language-Azure" data-lang="Azure">az appconfig feature show -n NameOfTheAppConfiguration --key .appconfig.featureflag/NameOfTheFeatureFlag --subscription xxx
</code></pre>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and Hosting an AI Solution Using Prompt Flow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/creating-and-hosting-an-ai-solution-using-prompt-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/creating-and-hosting-an-ai-solution-using-prompt-flow/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about why we chose the Prompt Flow. In the AI world, we wanted to have one place where we could build our AI solutions and we wanted to have platform where other developers could easily collaborate. And this is a great use case for Prompt Flow, which works as an orchestration tool for our builds.
We built two solutions. Our vision was to get metadata from some article and alternative text from pictures, and then each solution needed a final step: a translator to translate the results into different languages.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about why we chose the Prompt Flow.
In the AI world, we wanted to have one place where we could build our AI solutions and  we wanted to have platform where other developers could easily collaborate. And this is a great use case for Prompt Flow, which works as an orchestration tool for our builds.</p>
<p>We built two solutions. Our vision was to get metadata from some article and alternative text from pictures, and then each solution needed a final step: a translator to translate the results into different languages.</p>
<p>And these two solutions were created through the Prompt Flow. <a href="https://github.com/radekpadrta/MamboJambo_PromptFlow">Source code here</a></p>
<p>When we built the solution through Prompt Flow, our next step was to create an endpoint where the solution could be hosted and wait for travelers (requests).</p>
<h3 id="how-did-we-do-that">How Did We Do That?</h3>
<p>When we create builds on Prompt flow, we used the Machine Learning Workspace, which also has an option to create the endpoint. Creating the endpoint was a simple task, but how could we assign the Prompt Flow solution to the endpoint, right?</p>
<h3 id="where-the-fun-begins">Where the Fun Begins</h3>
<p>The solution needs to be packaged first, and that the need for us to create a <strong>model</strong> in MLW. It means: Prompt Flow build become a Model. Once we have the model, we can create an empty endpoint, which will wait for our model. However, to complete this, we need to create an Environment.</p>
<p>The Environment for building our model needs to be somehow added to the endpoint, and the environment is something that will handle the deployment. If you remember from the start, I mentioned that our use case also needed a translator, right? This is a small problem for the environment because we can&rsquo;t use a pre-built environment and we need to create our own.</p>
<h3 id="why">Why?</h3>
<p>The translator isn&rsquo;t included by default in Prompt Flow, but you can install packages in Prompt Flow. That is why you need to have the package also in your environment. We used a predefined image and we added the RUN command for the translator package. That is how we built the environment through Dockerfile and ACR. We hosted the Docker image in Azure Container Registry.</p>
<p>Ok, we have Prompt Flow (Builds) - Model - Endpoint (Empty) - Environment. So what is the next and the last step to push travelers(request) to the castle(endpoint) ?</p>
<h3 id="deployment-facing-the-final-boss">Deployment: Facing the Final Boss</h3>
<p>Deployment
This is last boss who is waiting for us and need to be finished. Here we need to gather all the information about our previous road - model, environment, and the endpoint need to be entered to the deployment, but we also need to provide SKU (VM) and assign the traffic.</p>
<p>Then if we get green light, the boss is finished and our castle can welcome travelers.</p>
<p>More about the project will be added soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</guid>
      <description>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.
I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.</p>
<p>I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare. It&rsquo;s not much time to prepare. If you have full time job and energetic girlfriend.</p>
<h3 id="my-study-plan">My study plan</h3>
<p>My study plan is a bit different from others certifications. I want to focus mainly on practice exams and analyze the areas where I failed during the exams. This should help me better understand the topics where I am weak, allowing me to skip over the things that don&rsquo;t need much improvement.</p>
<h3 id="first-practice-exam-attempt">First Practice Exam Attempt</h3>
<p>I made my first attempt today on the Azure portal and scored only 44%.</p>
<p>However, I don&rsquo;t feel bad about it. Scoring 44% on the first attempt is good, and I realized that I was just making some dumb mistakes and I was a bit hurry. Looking forward to next improvements.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/">Road to Azure v2</a>
<a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/">Road to Azure v3</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
