<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>AZ104 on Radek Padrta</title>
    <link>http://localhost:52261/tags/az104/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AZ104 on Radek Padrta</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:52261/cloudhammer.svg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:52261/cloudhammer.svg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:52261/tags/az104/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104 - Done 🎉</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52261/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:52261/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/</guid>
      <description>Few days before exam For my last preparation, I reviewed John Savill&amp;rsquo;s Study Cram which can be found here Road to Azure v2. And I did one test with 50-60 questions (about 1-2 hour for each) every day. Two days ago I got only 70% and the mood was not ok. I tested myself in my hometown when I visited my family so there was distraction to get the test done.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="few-days-before-exam">Few days before exam</h3>
<p>For my last preparation, I reviewed John Savill&rsquo;s Study Cram which can be found here <a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/">Road to Azure v2</a>. And I did one test with 50-60 questions (about 1-2 hour for each) every day. Two days ago I got only 70% and the mood was not ok. I tested myself in my hometown when I visited my family so there was distraction to get the test done. I woke up early the next day before the test day and tried another exam and I got 92%, so it gave me some confidence.</p>
<p>In the evening I watched the last 1 hour from Study cram and then I shut down my brain. I wanted to not think about the exam, just think about the present moment.</p>
<h3 id="test-day">Test day</h3>
<p>I took the exam at 8AM so I woke up at 6AM, got a huge breakfast from my girlfriend, watched some YT videos, hit the toilet a few times and then I went to the exam. On the way to the test center I listened to some dopamine boost music. Then I hit the toilet one more time and here we go.</p>
<h3 id="the-two-hour-challenge">The Two-Hour Challenge</h3>
<p>The test was for two hours, when I sat at the computer I wasn&rsquo;t really nervous as I was supposed to be in the past. It&rsquo;s just a certification..</p>
<p>But after a few questions I was nervous. The certification was really tough! I got thoughts like: &ldquo;When can I schedule the next attempt&rdquo;, &ldquo;I am totally confused&rdquo;, &ldquo;The time is ticking, no time&rdquo;.. and these thoughts made me nervous.
In another way there was still the spirit in a different part of my head, that said, fuck it be logical and just read the question, don&rsquo;t think so much about the question and just try to make it.</p>
<p>The spirit was the correct one.</p>
<h2 id="we-finished-it">We finished it!</h2>
<p>After 2 hours I saw the result and there was PASS. I didn&rsquo;t say anything in my head. I just smiled at the monitor. We managed it and we beat it!</p>
<p>Some of these questions were really something I hadn&rsquo;t experienced. And that means there is huge room to improve my skills!</p>
<p>And here are these:
<img loading="lazy" src="/AZCerts.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to Azure v1</a>
<a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/">Road to Azure v2</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104 v2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52261/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:52261/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/</guid>
      <description>How is it going with Road to AZ104?
At the start, I felt a lot of energy. I make at least one test every day, which takes approximately 1-2 hours.
I tested myself on Cloud Guru, Azure Learning, and I am newly testing myself on Examtopics, which was suggested by my colleague. There are actual questions from the exam, but I think the approach to memorizing them&amp;hellip; there is soo much question, I dont have brain for it:)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How is it going with <a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to AZ104</a>?</p>
<hr>
<p>At the start, I felt a lot of energy. I make at least one test every day, which takes approximately 1-2 hours.</p>
<p>I tested myself on Cloud Guru, Azure Learning, and I am newly testing myself on Examtopics, which was suggested by my colleague. There are actual questions from the exam, but I think the approach to memorizing them&hellip; there is soo much question, I dont have brain for it:)</p>
<p>Need to say I got a more than 70% only a few times&hellip;</p>
<p>In the meantime, I watched John Savill&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9DuTWSvsLXM&amp;t=3711s&amp;ab_channel=JohnSavill%27sTechnicalTraining">Networking Master Class</a>. Networking is a part that I am not strong in, so I am trying to work on it.</p>
<p>I also started watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Knf9nub4-k&amp;t=3275s&amp;ab_channel=JohnSavill%27sTechnicalTraining">Azure 104 Study Cram</a> from John Savill, which I think gave me a lot. I want to watch it one more time.</p>
<p>I need to mention, I don&rsquo;t take many notes. I take notes only if I fail on some questions, but I do not take notes through the videos. This can be a problem, but I need to think positively before the test. After the fight, we can try a different way.</p>
<p>The plan is to focus mainly next week on the exam and check the Study Cram one more time. And then take action!</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s see if we can make it :)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to Azure v1</a>
<a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/">Road to Azure v3</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52261/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:52261/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</guid>
      <description>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.
I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.</p>
<p>I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare. It&rsquo;s not much time to prepare. If you have full time job and energetic girlfriend.</p>
<h3 id="my-study-plan">My study plan</h3>
<p>My study plan is a bit different from others certifications. I want to focus mainly on practice exams and analyze the areas where I failed during the exams. This should help me better understand the topics where I am weak, allowing me to skip over the things that don&rsquo;t need much improvement.</p>
<h3 id="first-practice-exam-attempt">First Practice Exam Attempt</h3>
<p>I made my first attempt today on the Azure portal and scored only 44%.</p>
<p>However, I don&rsquo;t feel bad about it. Scoring 44% on the first attempt is good, and I realized that I was just making some dumb mistakes and I was a bit hurry. Looking forward to next improvements.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/">Road to Azure v2</a>
<a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v3/">Road to Azure v3</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
