<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>AZ104 on Radek Padrta</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/az104/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AZ104 on Radek Padrta</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/az104/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104 v2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104-v2/</guid>
      <description>How is it going with Road to AZ104?
At the start, I felt a lot of energy. I make at least one test every day, which takes approximately 1-2 hours.
I tested myself on Cloud Guru, Azure Learning, and I am newly testing myself on Examtopics, which was suggested by my colleague. There are actual questions from the exam, but I think the approach to memorizing them feels bad to me.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How is it going with <a href="https://www.radekpadrta.cz/zet/articles/road-to-az104/">Road to AZ104</a>?</p>
<hr>
<p>At the start, I felt a lot of energy. I make at least one test every day, which takes approximately 1-2 hours.</p>
<p>I tested myself on Cloud Guru, Azure Learning, and I am newly testing myself on Examtopics, which was suggested by my colleague. There are actual questions from the exam, but I think the approach to memorizing them feels bad to me.</p>
<p>I need to say I got a score of more than 70% only a few times&hellip;</p>
<p>In the meantime, I watched John Savill&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9DuTWSvsLXM&amp;t=3711s&amp;ab_channel=JohnSavill%27sTechnicalTraining">Networking Master Class</a>. Networking is a part that I am not strong in, so I am trying to work on it.</p>
<p>I also started watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Knf9nub4-k&amp;t=3275s&amp;ab_channel=JohnSavill%27sTechnicalTraining">Azure 104 Study Cram</a> from John Savill, which I think gave me a lot. I want to watch it one more time.</p>
<p>I need to mention, I don&rsquo;t take many notes. I take notes only if I fail on some questions, but I do not take notes through the videos. This can be a problem, but I need to think positively before the test. After the fight, we can try a different way.</p>
<p>The plan is to focus mainly next week on the exam and check the Study Cram one more time. And then take action!</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s see if we can make it :)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to AZ104</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/road-to-az104/</guid>
      <description>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.
I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I started to prepare for a new certification, AZ-104. As a Cloud Engineer who mainly works with Azure, this certification is one of the must-haves.</p>
<p>I made it as my main quest for this month to push myself and stay committed, I already scheduled the onsite exam for July 29th at 8 AM. I believe that early time is the best for me to be sharp and this gives me 25 days to prepare. It&rsquo;s not much time to prepare. If you have full time job and energetic girlfriend.</p>
<h3 id="my-study-plan">My study plan</h3>
<p>My study plan is a bit different from others certifications. I want to focus mainly on practice exams and analyze the areas where I failed during the exams. This should help me better understand the topics where I am weak, allowing me to skip over the things that don&rsquo;t need much improvement.</p>
<h3 id="first-practice-exam-attempt">First Practice Exam Attempt</h3>
<p>I made my first attempt today on the Azure portal and scored only 44%.</p>
<p>However, I don&rsquo;t feel bad about it. Scoring 44% on the first attempt is good, and I realized that I was just making some dumb mistakes and I was a bit hurry. Looking forward to next improvements.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
