<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Madeira on Radek Padrta</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/madeira/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Madeira on Radek Padrta</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cloudhammer.svg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/madeira/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on Madeira</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/reflection-on-madeira/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zet/articles/reflection-on-madeira/</guid>
      <description>We are in Madeira, our fifth day here. Overall, I am really enjoying my time on this beautiful Portuguese island&amp;hellip; It is giving me really good practice in driving!
New road And it is a good time to reflect on my journey and set new plans for myself. There were a few changes in the last week, one of them being about my job. I decided to accept a new job offer, which means there will be a lot of new opportunities to learn in few weeks.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are in Madeira, our fifth day here. Overall, I am really enjoying my time on this beautiful Portuguese island&hellip; It is giving me really good practice in driving!</p>
<h3 id="new-road">New road</h3>
<p>And it is a good time to reflect on my journey and set new plans for myself. There were a few changes in the last week, one of them being about my job. I decided to accept a new job offer, which means there will be a lot of new opportunities to learn in few weeks. From job interviews and some of my own research, I feel like it was a good decision, and I believe it will have also a huge impact on my journey as the current job!</p>
<h3 id="home-business">Home business</h3>
<p>The second thing is about our home business. We have finished all the prep, we made a strategy, and now we are going all in. It requires some investments from our side, mainly time, which is the most valuable thing for us, but we believe it is something we can do over the next 10 years as a hobby. So LFG :)</p>
<h3 id="online-presence">Online Presence</h3>
<p>The third thing is about online presence. It means being more active from my side in sharing on social media. I chose LinkedIn, which is also a good place to share my journey, and I will start posting on Instagram. I have a small idea about the content, but this will need to wait for a few days until I am back home.</p>
<p>In the meantime, you can see a few pictures from Madeira and more on my <a href="https://www.instagram.com/_rapad/">Instagram</a>, don&rsquo;t hesitate to connect with me there.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/madeira1.jpg" type="" alt=""  />
<img loading="lazy" src="/madeira2.jpg" type="" alt=""  />
<img loading="lazy" src="/madeira3.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
